Hello everyone.
In this session
I will talk about video and subtitles.
My name is Masaya Hayashi.
I joined the WordPress community in 2013.
After that, I once spoke at a WordCamp.
This is the second time.
Last year, I was a organiser at WordCamp Ogijima 2018.
I'm contributing for WordPress.tv.
On SNS,
my nickname is Haya2_
I am joining,
Twitter and YouTube etc.
If you could,
I hope you will follow me.
First of all, I would like to talk about the video.
What do you imagine when you heard the video?
when you heard the video?
YouTuber?
Stylish videos?
Does anyone have heard of the word Vlogger?
Not a weblog blog.
VLOG.
It is the word "Vlogger".
This is a style of making videos more everyday, and using videos to express things like blogs that have been expressed with text and images.
To make everyday life into videos.
Perhaps, you might think "Are such videos interesting?"
I believe that it would be coming more and more from now on these videos.
.
I think that the world where videos become everyday will soon come.
I think that the people can communicate with people all arond the world with videos with fun.
Again, I will talk about WordPress and videos.
I have a question for you.
What is this number?
11,405
The answer is "The number of videos published on WordPress.tv".
This is WordPress.tv.
This site is displayed when you type "wordpress.tv" on your browser.
Word Press.tv is a web service for sharing videos.
Speaking of web services for sharing videos,
One of the most famous is YouTube.
I think it's like that.
The difference is
only videos related to WordPress are uploaded.
The videos uploaded here are ...
Creative Commons.
CC BY-SA 4.0
Another question.
What is this number?
The answer is.
The number of WordCamps held in Japan which session videos are uploaded to WordPress.tv.
So far, there have been about 25 WordCamps in Japan.
.
Not all videos of WordCamp held Japan is in it.
Here are 18 WordCamps that held in Japan.
However, not all session videos are uploaded for that 18 WordCamps.
You can watch videos of these WordCamp sessions. This is WordPress.tv.
This is off topic, but,
I want to publish videos from all WordCamps.
So, if you have data for unpublished session videos.
If you want to share your session video, I would love to hear from you.
Next, I will talk about the workflow of the WordCamp session video is released on WordPress.tv.
The whole overlooking First, then, make a plan.
Equipment.
Wiring.
Placement.
Recording.
Edit.
Submit.
And it becomes a flow of release.
I will talk about video data.
This is a commercial law story about how to associate video data.
There have been many sort of medias that can save videos so far.
As of today,
I think SD cards are the most used.
Since SD cards can be purchased at convenience stores, etc., and they are also inexpensive, I think there are many people who know.
The video data is saved there. But,
You sould check maximum file size for one video.
.
Videos are typically very large compared to text and images.
Normally, when you save data on the SD card.
Please note that the size of 2 GB may not be able to save any more file size.
Care should also be taken when sharing such large data online.
The speed of the line is also important, and a lot of data.
In a short time. If you do so, there may be a case where the network speed is limited and the speed is extremely slow even if the speed limit is limited.
It is necessary to handle video data while paying attention to these points.
There are various types of video formats.
What is the most major format I think of today?
I think, it is H.264.
It is also called a file format extension for moving images.
Roughly speaking,
When I talk to you.
Many of the file formats such as MP4 and MOV are used.
Next is a very important point.
The maximum capacity of the video that can be up to WordPress.tv
1 GB.
I think the size is very small.
Therefore, various ingenuity is required to keep it to 1 GB.
One approach is resolution.
Recently there is a size called Full HD(1080p).
Often used, but ...
And press. For videos on wordpress.tv,
Up to a size 720p is good.
I think that is appropriate.
In addition, the factor of how much movement can be expressed in time units is related to bit rate.
I think about this recently.
Bit rate is.
For example, it is often set to 10 Mbps.
However, When uploading to WordPress.tv, the bit rate must be reduced to about 2Mbps.
Next, I will give an example of the equipment lists.
This is me.
Last year at WordCamp Ogijima.
It will be a list when you were involved in the same section.
Video camera.
tripod.
Voice recorder.
Microphone cable.
Microphone microphone connector conversion connector.
Shotgun microphone.
Microphone stand.
OA tap.
It was listed because it would be necessary.
I will look at some of these in detail.
First, camera.
In general, video cameras called handy cams are the most commonly used to create long-time videos.
Sometimes such a camera is used, but,
.
I think it's for advanced users.
Next is the microphone.
When recording with the microphone attached to the camcorder.
There is a possibility that the sound cannot be picked up sound well because of distance between the microphone and the speaker is too far.
There is a shotgun microphone as a microphone to cope with such a situation.
The microphone This is where there is a directional
Just in the direction of the external microphone.
It becomes a microphone that can pick up the generated sound intensively.
this is,.
last year,.
A microphone actually used on a WordCamp Ogijima.
In addition to this switcher splitter, video capture devices,
If you have a GPU-equipped PC, you can take more advanced shots.
Next, I will talk about the layout and wiring diagram.
Before making a list, it is very important to make a diagram when considering the assumption that you can use it when you go to the venue. .
Even if you're probably ready, your cables are not long enough to actually go to the scene.
There are many cases where unexpected things happen, such as connector type is different.
It is recommended to make a layout diagram in advance to cope with this.
Next, I will talk about how to edit videos.
macOS, iOS, iPad OS.
If you're using an Apple Apple device like that, you probably have an iMovie app.
I think that can be installed at no additional cost.
In this iMovie.
First, cut and paste a video called trimming.
It comes with a function.
In addition, it also has the ability to rotate the video.
You can export as MOV file.
You can enlarge the video.
Also called transition.
When moving from one scene to another.
Suddenly Rather than there is a cut, a function that it is a variety of production Toka or switched to take a little Toka or switched floaty curtain,
iMovie will have.
Conversely, what iMovie can't do.
One is mosaic/blur.
There are times.
Something such as a password has been displayed in the video.
In that case, instead of cutting only that part, I just want to leave the part where the password is displayed.
In such a case, the mosaic and blur functions are necessary.
However, this mosaic and blur function is quite advanced editing.
If you want to use these functions, you will need special software or software with more advanced editing functions.
Also, when recording with an external microphone, only the left side is producing sound.
You might. It depends on microphones.
In such a case, iMovie can not edit. so that you can hear the sound of only one side. not both sides.
The bit rate cannot be set.
On the WordPress.tv, there is an video which introduced how to edit videos with iMovie.
There is also a video of the procedure of editing a work camp video that edits the video.
If you are interested, click here See also.
Next, talk to those who use Windows.
If you are using Windows, there will be an icon called Video Editor in the Start menu.
When you click here, it seems that an application called Photo is actually started, but.
You can edit the video in "Photo" app.
What you can do with video editor
Cut and paste trimming video.
Rotation of the moving image
it can export MP4 file.
.
What can not be reversed.
Mosaic/blur.
The expansion of the video
Transition.
This area will be to the functions possible with iMovie, but if it is here of video editor, you can not function.
In addition, you can hear the sound of only one side on both sides and set the bit rate.
if,
like this.
If you need advanced editing.
For example,.
Take an example.
Premiere Pro of Adobe.
Black Magic Design Davinci Resolve.
These apps can do more advanced editing.
However, it is difficult to compare with iMovie and Video Editor, and it is difficult because it is an advanced high function.
However, I hope that you will be interested in this kind of apps and be able to edit videos more and more.
I am thinking.
It was not possible in the previous application, mosaic or blur
Try to hear one side of the sound on both sides.
Set the bit rate finely.
On the other hand, using these software, it can be easily realized.
Also in the previous introduce the iMovie and video editor
Be devastated.
There is no such technique as adding such a blur, but it is rather difficult.
There are also things like that.
To select the application in accordance with the necessary edits.
That's important.
Recently on YouTube.
There are a lot of videos explaining how to use these video editing software, so if you are interested, you can watch them.
The edited video is then sent to Word Press. When uploading to a TV, enter necessary information in such a home and post it.
I would like to say a few points.
For categories.
The location of the venue. Osaka today.
The year it was held again.
If this time, check this 2019.
And check the WordCamp video.
Automatically at the event name,
Contains information about the WordCamp.
It is a little small. I'm sorry.
Around here,
The event name.
In addition, no input is required for the producer.
If you go down the screen, it will look like this.
Since there is a item called the video file in the bottom of the item,
this.
Select a file from here.
Then press the submit button.
You can post the video.
To upload such a word camp video to WordPress.tv have videos are also introduced to WordPress.tv. Please check it out If you have any interest.
There is a minimum amount of information in the contents that I put in the previous home,
but there are cases where I want to share information with some supplements.
As an example, if you want to specify the address of the actual video page called "slug" in detail.
Also, if you want to tag the video for that video theme, there is no item to enter in the previous home.
-
It becomes necessary to share information using such a sheet sharing sheet.
Next, I will talk about work sharing.
I think there is work sharing in Web production, but work sharing can also be considered when dealing with videos.
First, a small group.
In this case, the word camp executive committee thinks that the movie file that created the movie file will be an SD card,
but it will be put together, cut the movie, and sometimes in the first part of the movie called intro .
Such added pictures and short video, encodes the video by editing such processed to.
And submit on that.
If you do all of this work by yourself.
There is also a word camp like this.
For example, in the case of the word camp Ogijima that I was in charge of last year,
since the number of sessions was a degree 5 and 6, it was possible the corresponding thing in my one person.
However, in the case of Tokyo and Osaka, there are cases where the number of sessions is 30, so in that case one person will respond.
I think it's difficult.
Another point I would like to explain in the contents of this slide is the moderator.
WordPress.tv is different from YouTube.
In WordPress.tv, people check the video when you publish the video to WordPress.tv.
Word Press. TV is to upload a video about WordPress, so if the content is not related to WordPress at all,
or if it is judged that the content is not suitable for the WordPress community,
the video may not be released There is.
It is the moderator who performs such work.
There are about 30 to 40 moderators in the world.
Two people including me in Japan.
Next, I will tell you an a case of a large number of people.
Share the previous work in this way. First, the person who uploads the shot video to the cloud.
Next, do you create an information organization sheet?
Next, the person who creates the intro.
Finally, it takes video editing and submitting.
Each can involve multiple people.
The work management of these people is ...
You can do that using a spreadsheet like the one you just mentioned.
By corresponding in this manner, without delay video editing even with a larger word camp
I think we can proceed.
Next, I will talk about subtitles.
Speaking of subtitles, for example, when you go to a movie theater to watch a movie.
Japanese subtitles are added to words spoken in English.
I think this is the most familiar subtitle for Japanese people.
Needless to say, the contents of the English session can be understood in Japanese.
There is a significance.
However,.
There are many other types of subtitles, each of which has significance.
For example, if English subtitles are added to English videos.
Even people who are not good at listening to English have the significance of making it easier to understand English.
You can understand the contents even in an environment where no sound can be produced.
In addition, you can also know the contents of the human it is difficult to hear sound.
Add English subtitles to Japanese videos.
you canl study English.
Probably in this room, but I think that such a person is not,
For those who can not understand Japanese language will be able to understand the video in English language.
The work to put such a variety of subtitles, we are in the WordPress.tv team.
Next, we will introduce an example of how to create a subtitle file.
The first one is,.
Edit there with a text editor.
It is a method.
Subtitle data.
Simply put, it can be created as a text file with timing and display characters.
So, I think that can be relatively easily edit if such a level.
However, it can be quite time consuming and time consuming.
So, recently, a challenge has been made to make this work more efficient using various technologies.
Among them, what I want to introduce this time is an app called UD Talk.
This can be a little tricky to use, but if you can use it, it will be a very efficient application for adding subtitles.
UDTalk is not an app mainly for adding subtitles.
UDTalk is communication support app.
That is the original development and purpose concept.
However, since this app has a powerful function, it is also a very useful application as an auxiliary application for adding subtitles.
I will talk about the benefits of using UD Talk.
The first one is,.
It's easier than starting from scratch because it will transcribe what you said.
The second is,.
This means that when a person who speaks speaks, the characters are written in real time on the spot,
but the current technology often has a wrong recognition that is different from what was heard.
In such cases, multiple people can fix that subtitle at the same time in real time.
This is a very powerful feature.
The third. Period and comma is in sentences.
The fourth is word registration.
For example, if you had a WordPress terminology, words like Word Camp probably won't be transcribed correctly with many modern technologies.
However, if you register such words, you will be able to recognize the character recognition speech correctly and transcribe.
I think this is also a very strong strength of UD Talk at the moment.
Finally, timing information is entered.
The task of adding subtitles is to make the content you paid for text and the timing of the information of the text after that,
but the task of adding this timing is also a very steady work It becomes.
So, if you use UD Talk, the text with the approximate timing will be prepared, which is very useful as the original data for adding subtitles.
However, there are many different formats for subtitle data.
So, by doing a lot of conversion and changing the data format, you can finally upload to the WordPress.tv.
In general, it is a CSV converter.
one more,.
Web service, Amara.org
This is not necessarily something that must be this, but as an example this time I will introduce it as the most used one now.
CSV format.
I think this is probably what many people have seen.
Each item in the text file is separated by a comma.
That is in CSV format.
An SRT case that lacks a CSV converter and can be used with Facebook videos.
Also, SBV format that can be used on YouTube etc.
The developer of UD Talk has developed a function to convert to the format.
Here is an example of SRT format.
A serial number is assigned and contains timing information and text information.
I think that it is a relatively simple form.
Next, Amara.org.
Introducing the subtitle data editing service.
This is free to use.
You can use UDtalk for free.
You can use Amara.org for free.
How to read the screen.
The contents of the middle part are included as text.
This allows you to edit individual texts on the browser.
Furthermore, in the middle part of this.
It stretches by pulling to the side.
Here is.
As an example here.
If you are playing a taiko master game, it will be easy to understand. The letters flow from the right.
And by pressing the keyboard at the moment when the scolding person hits the letter.
It becomes an application that can put the timing.
And like this.
Through various operations, the next is the DFXT format.
This is one of the formats called XML.
I think that.
However, when it comes to this point, I think that it is impossible to edit with an editor by hand.
This lower part, here.
"&#12428;"
This represents one Japanese character, but it is impossible to edit the changed player directly in the editor.
So, edit the data using the various tools I mentioned earlier.
It can last to be files to upload from a form of Word Press.tv a file called TTML format, be to submit, you can add subtitles.
This form is very simple, author's name and e-mail address
Then select the subtitle language to post and attach the subtitle file at the end.
And can submit.
In the format.
Here even after the post, will be published by a moderator is to work approve it
It explained now, subtitling, and, to post WordPress.tv, also a procedure that, because there is a commentary video WordPress.tv,
Those who would like a closer look, See also here.
Next, I will talk about moderators.
This is operated by the moderator. This is the WordPress.tv screen.
As you probably know, WordPress.tv is a video sharing site made of WordPress.
Each video will be posted as a post.
Moderators can log in to this WordPress management screen.
This moderator.
It consists of WordPress.tv team.
As I said earlier, around 30 to 40 in the world.
Meeting is held in Slack every week.
A chat meeting will be held.
WordPress community official Slack #WPTV channel every Friday.
From midnight in Japan time.
If you are interested, please join us as it is open.
I also communicated with the WordCamp organiser members using the information sharing sheet that I showed you a bit earlier.
This information sharing sheet is also used to exchange supplementary data necessary for uploading.
The story so far is When handling videos and subtitles on WordPress.tv.
I will talk to you.
From here, I want to talk about comparing WordPress.tv and YouTube.
WordPress.tv, the size limit is 1 GB.
YouTube size limit is 120 GB.
I don't think it's a comparison.
The overwhelming strength of YouTube.
The great feature of YouTube is that it also supports videos such as high resolution 4K video, and introduce other videos that you may be interested in.
You can use the shortcut keys to decrease the numbers from 0 to 9 to jump 0% ~90% , and increase the decrease play speed.
You can move forward and back a little.
Word Press.tv will have the ability to change the speed.
However, other features when compared to YouTube,
It is difficult to compare.
However,.
Though my thinking, it may also risk that depends on one of the cloud service
Personally, I believe that good is to use both YouTube and WordPress.tv is.
Excuse me. Although the explanation was around, YouTube has a channel called WordPress.
This is WordPress. Some of the videos on TV have been reprinted. If you are interested in this channel.
Please subscribe.
Regardless of the place, anyway, I want to make more videos.
The ideal situation.
I expect that many people will be able to watch videos,
so that the motivation to publish videos will improve and many high-quality videos will be released.
But the reality is ...
Even you publish a video, access is less.
And the motivation to publish videos is down.
The quality of the video will decline, the release time will be delayed, and there will be no subtitles.
How can I make a better flow?
I opened WordPress site. The title is "Let's be friends with the world by WordPress.tv.
I created this personally now.
I made a @WPTVJP account to Twitter
I would like everyone to follow this.
I have few friends now.
However, the future, by which I am looking at a lot more people WordPress.tv, become the world with friends. I would like to make such a era.
I have a few suggestions.
First, why don't you add English subtitles to the content of your session?(Like this :))
Then, there is a possibility that people around the world will be able to see what you have entered in Japanese.
Next, why don't you premiere on YouTube?
Here, ...
I think we can create an event that makes it easier to watch uploaded videos.
Third, give feedback on the video.
There is "Like" icon below a video.
If you have a account of WordPress.com, you can "Like" it.
I'd like to ask for reactions to uploaded videos.
There is a workspace of Slack called WordSlack.
Here in Japanese.
You can communicate about WordPress.
We look forward in this #wptv channel.
Please join.
You can find the movie that explains about WordSlack in YouTube. I explained it.
I hope #wptv channel will be a place where many people who like videos gather and communicate creatively.
In summary,
I will omit it because of time. I told you about this.
Now, that's it.
Thank you for watching.